Hillel Steinmetz

ABOUT ME

I'm a writer and analyst based in Chicago, with one year of behavioral science research experience. I'm currently working as a Data Journalist at Saggezza, a consulting firm in Chicago with a focus on technology. I love to learn, and I'm always interested in finding new ways to challenge myself.

EXPERIENCE

Saggezza, Chicago, IL

Data Journalist, November 2020 – Present

- Created content to highlight the technical solutions the IT consulting firm developed for clients
- Wrote about AI, cloud data management, and data visualization for marketing content and articles

University of Chicago Department of Psychology, Chicago, IL

Research Assistant, June 2019 – August 2020

- Developed survey battery in Qualtrics to study the effects of civic engagement on college students
- Collected and analyzed data from 20+ participants using Excel and R to isolate mediating factors
- Facilitated lab operations; taught graduate students to use software and resolved technical issues

University of Chicago Department of Psychology, Chicago, IL

Undergraduate Research Assistant, February 2018 – June 2019

- Designed two experiments—collected and/or created 120+ image and sound stimuli, edited these stimuli in linguistic software, and wrote computer scripts to present study tasks and analyze data
- Created visual summaries of data sets and presented these findings at a symposium

EDUCATION

The University of Chicago, Chicago, IL

Bachelor of Arts in Linguistics, June 2019

Cumulative GPA 3.92/4.00 | Major GPA 4.00/4.00

Honors and Grants: Leonard Bloomfield Prize in Linguistics, PRISM Research Grant, Phi Beta Kappa

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Languages: Hebrew (fluent), French (working proficiency)
- Computer: R, HTML, JavaScript (basic), Python (intermediate), Excel, Qualtrics, SPSS